Rocio Galvan

CONTACT

757.744.9779

web.dev.rocio@gmail.com

Raleigh, NC

in linkedin.com/in/rocio-galvan

EXPERTISE

Communication

Planning & implementing

Time management

Customer contracts

People management

Customer Service

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Third-Party APIs

Server-Side APIs

Libraries:

- -Bootstrap & Bootswatch
- Bulma

Node.js & Express.js

SQL & MySQL2

Model-View-Controller (MVC)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Inquisitive learner and leader able to communicate on a global level. Using my prior business acumen, I can produce thorough work while managing strict deadlines to achieve the company goals. I'm excited to combine my technical full-stack developer training with my past corporate experience to improve procedures and exceed customer expectations.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Export Air/Ocean Agent

Expeditors / Raleigh, NC / 03/2021 - 01/2022

- Engaged customers to determine shipping needs & gathed compliance docs
- Managed all of the air export accounts for the Raleigh, NC branch
- Submitted customs export filings and verified/entered rates before invoicing
- Coordinated with overseas agents for rates, new requests and approvals
- Cross trained on ocean export process & temperature controlled shipments

Assistant Manager

Lidl / Raleigh, NC & Virginia Beach, VA / 03/2020 - 03/2021

- Completed intensive 4 month training leading up to a final test and passed on first attempt
- Managed store operations by prioritizing tasks & aligning them to individual strengths, organizing breaks, driving shelf-stocking speeds, solving customer issues all while completing my own tasks
- Upheld quality standards by providing feedback, coaching or praising 21 team members
- Placed orders based on sales analytics & maintained system by fixing inventory discrepancies

Customer Service Officer

Holcim / Melbourne, Australia / 03/2018 - 09/2018

- Precisely input phone/email orders and entered into dispatch spreadsheet and system, taking care both matched 100% to avoid costly and time consuming errors
- Liaised hourly with construction engineers, quarries, dispatchers, truckers and account managers on new orders and followed up on existing ones
- Initiated and helped create an improved aggregate product spreadsheet to include sizes, colors, quarry availability, alternate names and special notes of each material

Guest Service Agent

Lizard Island / Lizard Island, Australia / 09/2017 - 02/2018

 Went above and beyond to ensure memorable experiences were created at a luxury 5-star resort

Rocio Galvan

LANGUAGES

English - Native

Spanish – Proficient

AWARDS

Expeditors Spot Award- July 2021

WORK EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

- Greeted guests at airport and drove them on a detailed point of interests tour in a 8 seater buggy while keeping them engaged
- Part of a collaborative team effort in triple checking guest reservation files for a flawless check-in
- Created daily flight manifests and coordinated car transfers to and from the island for each guest

Export Premiere Representative-VIP

CMA CGM / Norfolk, VA / 01/2015 - 12/2016

- Oversaw export bookings & documentation for 5 premiere customers like Weber grill and Nestlé
- Interpreted customer specific contracts for queries about rates, routes and surcharges
- Verified loading appointments were adhered to and containers made railroad and vessel cutoffs
- Liaised with HQ, overseas offices, trade, sales, intermodal, and customers to resolve issues
- Maintained bi-weekly customer calls to ensure smooth daily operations

Inbound Vessel Coordinator

CMA CGM / Norfolk, VA / 09/2013 - 01/2015

- Meticulously completed 22 steps every 2 weeks and saw the vessel through from start to finish
- Sent arrival notices & ensured documents, payment, & Customs clearance were received prior to release
- Ensured releases and free time were in place at ports & rail to avoid charges to the customer or service failure

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Developer Course

The University of North Carolina at Charlotte / NC / 02/2022 - 05/2022

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration

The University of North Carolina at Greensboro / Greensboro, NC / 2008 - 2012

Exchange Student

Università Carlo Cattaneo / Castellanza, Italy / 02/2011 - 06/2011